MARAT FAKHREEV

FRONT-END ENGINEER

Kazan, Russia +7 (951) 891-72-33

maratfakhreev.com marat.fakhreev@gmail.com github.com/maratfakhreev linkedin.com/in/maratfakhreev medium.com/@maratfakhreev

PROFILE

I'm front-end engineer with more than 10 years experience. I like CSS, Javascript and absolutely everything related to these technologies in the world of web and mobile development. I try to be a perfectionist in everything I do, pay attention to details in any UI/UX solution. I like writing both useful and not too much code in my free time. I'm a big fan of open source projects. Take a moment to explore crazy and demanded things from the programming world and the real world as well:)

EXPERIENCE

FRONT-END LEAD ENGINEER, REVEALBOT, USA, 2018-PRESENT

I've responsible for the development of the architecture and final features in main client. This client is part of huge distributed application that provides convenient tools that automate ad management strategies, launch new ad companies with bunch of variations and analyze insights based on current working process. All of this are for popular ad platforms such Facebook/Google/TikTok etc. The distinctive feature of the app without exaggeration is the best UI/UX in industry which also competitors try and most often fail to copy:). Core technologies are Vue, JSX, CSS-in-JS, Webpacker, Ruby on Rails.

FRONT-END/MOBILE ENGINEER, MAYAK, RUSSIA, 2020-PRESENT

Part time/on demand experience in one of the leading marketplaces analytics service in Russia. I've launched and developed client architecture for chrome plugin and simple mobile application (iOS/Android) which embed detailed statistic for different sellers, brands and goods right in the marketplaces pages. The main goal was to create super fast thin and responsive part of product that essentially brings the user to the main part of the service. So everything was based on pure javascript and development principles were built around simplicity and performance. Core

technologies for plugin: Vanilla javascript, Preact, Chrome plugin API. Mobile app based on Expo and React Native.

FRONT-END ENGINEER, CINARRA SYSTEMS, RUSSIA, 2017-2018

I was responsible for front-end part of huge RTB application. This part allows clients to form an advertising company, specify the target audience and also monitor its effectiveness on the basis of multiple metrics. Core technologies are React, Redux, Recompose and other FP stuff.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER/LEAD DEVELOPER, FLATSTACK, RUSSIA, 2013-2017 I was responsible for front-end part of different projects with different complexity and field of activity. Here at different time I was a part of 3-10 people size teams which provide full development cycle. I've tried popular FE-frameworks like React, Angular, Backbone/Marionette, also gained experience in varying degrees with technologies such as Node.js on BE, Cordova/Phonegap as mobile framework.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER, DARING AND YOUNG, RUSSIA, 2012-2013 I was responsible for front-end work of websites. Most projects were on Backbone.js and jQuery. Was mostly focused on interface markup and animation.

EDUCATION

2013-2015 Russia, Kazan State University. Master's degree in computer science. 2009-2013 Russia, Kazan State University. Bachelor's degree in computer science.

SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3/Pre-Post processors/CSS-in-JS
- JavaScript/TypeScript/CoffeeScript
- React, Preact, Flux/Redux, Vue, Vuex, Backbone/Marionette
- Vite/Esbuild/Webpack/Browserify/Gulp/Grunt
- Expo, React Native, Cordova, Electron
- Node.js, REST, JSON-API
- Chrome API, Messengers API for bots.
- Functional Programming, OOP, MVC, Unidirectional architectures

OPEN SOURCE

React-base, http://github.com/fs/react-base
React hot loader, https://github.com/gaearon/react-hot-loader

Marionette.js, https://github.com/marionettejs/backbone.marionette
Handlebars web pack plugin, https://github.com/sagold/handlebars-webpack-plugin
Backbone-base, http://github.com/fs/backbone-base

<u>Backbone ES6 Promise, https://github.com/maratfakhreev/backbone-es6-promise</u>

<u>Marionette Animated Region, https://github.com/maratfakhreev/marionette-animated-region</u>

Marionette Routes Helper, https://github.com/maratfakhreev/marionette-routes-helper Node telegram random message replier, https://github.com/maratfakhreev/node-telegram-random-message-replier

PET PROJECTS

DailySheet, daily-dev.com

<u>About</u>: Desktop application that accumulates useful feeds. Keeping you in touch with the latest news on technology. Whether you are a developer, manager, designer or just a cat lover like us, there is something to catch your eye or mind.

Role: Client app Developer, Website Front-end Developer.

<u>Stack</u>: Electron, Typescript, React + Redux, Styled components, Webpack, Ansible.

Stockroom, stockroom-dev.herokuapp.com

<u>About</u>: Service for accounting some goods via QR-codes. Primarily focused on owners of warehouses, stores and even offices that want to count their things.

Role: Front-end Developer.

Stack: React-on-Rails, Webpack, Rails, Heroku.